Southwest Folklore Center Field Recordings Collection 1943-ongoing
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Audio Recordings, 1943-ongoing; Series I
  - Wade Mainer and Julie Mainer, Old Time Mountain Music Concert, February 17, 1982; Tape 3 of 4 of the Old Time Mountain Music Concert co-sponsored by the University of Arizona's Southwest Folklore Center and the School of Music. Tape contains banjo songs performed by Wade and Julie Mainer... Drunkard's Hell -- No home, no home -- Put your hand in the hand of the man of Galilee -- Going to Georgia -- I have a clear title to a mansion -- Ezekial went down in the middle of the field -- Swing low sweet chariot -- Jonah -- Darby's ram -- Short Lou... Transcript available in 83.13/R.3.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 83.13, Folder R.3)
  - Wade Mainer, Julie Mainer, Bill Hensley, and Jim Griffith, Old Time Mountain Music Concert, February 17, 1982; Tape 4 of 4 of the Old Time Mountain Music Concert co-sponsored by the University of Arizona's Southwest Folklore Center and the School of Music. Tape contains songs with banjo accompaniment by Griffith... Scarlet purple robe -- The Arkansas traveller -- I saw the light... Between selections, Griffith and Mainer exchange, "Hey Stranger" jokes. Transcript available in 83.13/R.4.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 83.13, Folder R.4)
  - Bill Hensley, Interview, May 22, 1983; Tape contains interview with and banjo tunes performed by Hensley, recorded in Hensley's daughter's house, Tucson, AZ. Songs include: Pocahontas mine -- Charming Betsy -- Barlow knife -- John Henry (Cumberland Gap tuning) -- Silver chain -- Little birdie (Short Lu tuning). Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 83.14, Folder R.1)
  - Leon Taylor, Interview, August 21, 1977; Tape contains interview with songs performed by Taylor recorded at his home in Showlow, Arizona. Transcript indicates that Van Holyoak was also present during the interview. Instruments accompanying songs include fiddle, mandolin and guitar... Tennessee wagoneer -- Hobo Bill -- Lakes of Ponchartrain -- Fallen Leaves -- Caroline -- Gamblin' Blackie -- Just a small photo of my Mother -- Did you see my Daddy, Mister -- The Blind girl's prayer -- Will the roses bloom in heaven -- Mississippi moon -- Sidewalks of New York -- Jesse James -- Silver Bell -- Wheel of the wagon is broken -- Turkey in the straw -- My Mother was a lady -- Little Mary Fagan -- Floyd Collins... Transcript available in 83.1/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Showlow, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 10 in. (Box 83.15, Folder R.1)
  - Union Baptist Church, Prayers, December 19, 1979; Tape contains recorded prayer service, songs, and testimonies held at the Union Baptist Church, Florence, Arizona... Songs include: Let the light from the lighthouse shine -- Amazing grace -- I'm going to be so glad, when I get home -- It's going to rain -- So all we can do is pray in these changing times -- Life is a candle -- If the Lord should call me now -- Where He leads, I will follow... Transcript available in 83.16/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Florence, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 10 in. (Box 83.16, Folder R.1)
  - Billy Burkes, Interview, March 11, 1976; From Acquistions Inventory... tapes contain interview with Burke as he discusses his musical career as a singer and guitar player as well as working with Jimmie Rodgers. Transcripts available in 83.18/R.1.T and 83.18/R.2.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 2 sound tape reels, analog, 3 3/4 ips, 5 in. (Box 83.18, Folder R.1, R.2)
  - Chester James, Interview, January 7, 1976; Tape contains interview with and songs performed by Chester... Two little girls in blue -- Pleasant Sunday night -- Log cabin with the grapevine o'er the door -- On the hills of Kentucky -- Kincaid's theme song -- Born 4000 years ago -- The Engineer's child -- Little Joe... Transcript available in 83.19/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Phoenix, Arizona. 1 sound tape reels, analog, 5 in. (Box 83.19, Folder R.1)
  - Chester James, Interview, January 7, 1976; Tape contains interview with and songs performed by Chester... The Bug song -- Down by the railroad track -- Cross-eyed Sue -- Little shirt my mother made for me -- If I could be living when Jesus comes -- Shake hands with Mother again... Transcript available in 83.19/R.2.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Phoenix, Arizona. 1 sound tape reels, analog, 5 in. (Box 83.19, Folder R.2)
  - Sam Agins, Interview, October 9, 1975; Tape contains interview with songs and poems performed by Agins. Songs include: Letter edged in black -- A Peon named Pancho -- I just drifted in from Frisco -- Cowboy's home sweet home -- Poems include: Gullible buys a gold mine -- At 2 a.m. the station bell rang -- Wishin' and a fishin' -- Red Elk... Transcript available in 83.21/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in West Sedona, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 5 in. (Box 83.21, Folder R.1)
  - Van Holyoak, Interview, March 19, 1975; Tape contains interview, songs, stories and poems performed by Holyoak... Goldurn wheel -- Me and brother Bill -- Joe's favorite songs -- Patonia, pride of the plains -- Poems written for Joe Holyoak, Sr. -- Buckskin Joe -- Boomer Johnson -- Old Red -- Terry Sloan -- Windy Bill -- Franklin Ranch -- Clay Town Farm -- High chin' Bob -- Big wicked Bill -- Snug in my shack in the mountains -- My life story... Transcript available in 83.22/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith and Denny Carr in Clay Springs, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 10 in. (Box 83.22, Folder R.1)
  - Van Holyoak, Interview, March 19, 1975; Tape 2 of 3 contains interview, songs, stories and poems performed by Holyoak... Silver Jack -- Zebra dun -- Big Jim -- The Meanest man -- Last winter's vest -- Lone girl knoll -- How heaven should be -- Ozark Trail -- D-2 Horse wrangler -- Utah Carl -- Red River lullaby -- Skyball paint -- Frost on the cowboy's tarp -- Cowboy Jack -- When the work's all done this Fall -- One won't another will -- My love is a rider... stories on the tape tell about Holyoak's growing up years in Clay Springs, AZ. Transcript available in 83.22/R.2.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith and Denny Carr in Clay Springs, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 10 in. (Box 83.22, Folder R.2)
  - Van Holyoak, Interview, March 19, 1975; Tape 3 of 3 of interview with Holyoak contains a story about buying bargain milk cans at twelve cents each or eight for one dollar; reminiscences about learning songs and living in Clay Springs, AZ. in the 1930's and 1940's. Transcript available in 83.22/R.3.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith and Denny Carr in Clay Springs, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 10 in. (Box 83.22, Folder R.3)
  - Van Holyoak, Interview, October 10, 1975; Copy of tape made October 10, 1975, of interview with Holyoak contains stories, poems, and songs... The Black sheep -- Old Red -- Patonia, pride of the plains -- Red River lullaby -- Five of hearts on the wall -- Billy Venero... Transcript available in 83.22/R.4.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Clay Springs, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 3 3/4 ips, 5 in. (Box 83.22, Folder R.4)
  - Van Holyoak, Interview, October 10, 1975; Copy of tape made October 10, 1975, of interview with Holyoak contains stories, poems, and songs... Roy Bean -- Cowboy Jack -- Zebra dun -- Lone and painted cottage -- The Old apple tree -- He never came back -- Break the news to Mother... Transcript available in 83.22/R.5.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Clay Springs, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 3 3/4 ips, 5 in. (Box 83.22, Folder R.5)
  - Martha McNary Chilcote, Cowboy songs, August 11, 1983; Tape contains unaccompanied songs sung by Chilcote of Pinetop, Arizona... Cowboy's life/D-2 Horse wrangler -- Along side the Santa Fe Trail -- The Haunted falls -- Zebra dun -- Tyin' knots in the devil's tail -- Old Chisholm Trail -- On Monday, we had bread and gravy -- On Monday, we buy a new auto -- Ain't we crazy? -- Great Grand Dad... Transcript available in 83.23/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Pinetop, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 in. (Box 83.23, Folder R.1)
  - Mario Baeza, Folk Artists in Education Workshop, August 12, 1983; Tape contains interview with Baeza at the Folk Artists in Education Workshop, Showlow, AZ. Interview includes stories and songs... Alborrada -- Malagunea Salerosa -- El Caballo Prieto Azavache -- Polka... Transcript available in 83.24/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Showlow, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 in. (Box 83.24, Folder R.1)
  - Mario Baeza, Folk Artists in Education Workshop, August 12, 1983; Tape contains interview with Baeza at the Folk Artists in Education Workshop, Showlow, AZ. Interview includes stories and songs... La Lloroña -- Un Crusado -- Un Crusado en Palestina -- Cielito Lindo... Transcript available in 83.24/R.2.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Showlow, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 in. (Box 83.24, Folder R.2)
  - Gail Gardner, George German, Van Holyoak, and Glenn Ohrlin, Cowboy Concert, April 21, 1979; Tape contains songs performed by Gardner, German, Holyoak and Ohrlin at a concert, sponsored by the University of Arizona Student Activities Board and the Tucson Friends of Traditional Music, and hosted by James S. Griffith... Old Paint (German) -- Sierry Peaks (Gardner) -- My life story (Holyoak) -- High tone dance (Ohrlin) -- Whoopie ti yi ho, git along, little dogies (German) -- The Moonshine steer (Gardner) -- Story about a sermon on sex (Holyoak) -- Boomer Johnson (Holyoak) -- Punching the dough (Ohrlin) -- The Big corral (German) -- The Dude wrangler (Gardner)... Transcript available in 83.8/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 10 in. (Box 83.28, Folder R.1)
  - Gail Gardner, George German, Van Holyoak, and Glenn Ohrlin, Cowboy Concert, April 21, 1979; Tape 2 of 2 contains songs performed by Gardner, German, Holyoak and Ohrlin at a concert, sponsored by the University of Arizona Student Activities Board and the Tucson Friends of Traditional Music, and hosted by James S. Griffith... Story about kite flying (Holyoak) -- The Winged mustang (Holyoak) -- Story about pulling the calf (Ohrlin) -- Flip-flop and flies (Ohrlin) -- The Strawberry roan (German) -- I'm a hitchin' my wagon to the stars (German) -- The Cowman's troubles (Gardner) -- Story about a neutered dog (Holyoak) -- The Gol-darned wheel (Holyoak) -- Lee's Ferry (Ohrlin) -- Untitled song(German) -- Wild Bill Hickok's death (German) -- Untitled poem (Gardner) -- Frost on the cowboy's tarp (Holyoak) -- Story about two cowboys from Arizona in heaven (Griffith) -- Wild Horse Charlie (Ohrlin)... Transcript available in 83.28/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 10 in. (Box 83.28, Folder R.2)
  - New Hope Baptst Church sing, January 8, 1984; Tapes contains choir music performed by the New Hope Baptist Church choir, the Southside Presbyterian Church choir of Tucson, and the Gideon Baptist Church choir of Tucson. Program continues from reel to reel... New Hope Baptist Church choir: The Lord is my light / Praise ye the Lord /Up above my head (Laverne Falls, solo) / Salt of the earth (Denise Falls, solo) / We are blessed (Laura Fleming, solo) / I won't fear what man can do (Rose Walker, solo) / Leaning on the everlasting arms; Southside Presbyterian Church choir: I decided to make Jesus my choice / There is a brighter day ahead / Where could I go but to the Lord (James S. Griffith, solo) / I'll fly away (James S. Griffith, solo); Gideon Baptist Church choir: Rose Johnson, director / Sign me up (Angela Coleman, solo) / If you make a start, don't turn around (Dwight Hart, solo); Ken Warren Johnson: Prayer, Bible readings and sermon; Gideon Baptist Church choir: Ain't nobody can do me like Jesus / New name / Just keep the faith (Rose Johnson, solo)/ God be with you 'til we meet again. Collected by James S. Griffith in Casa Grande, Arizona. 4 sound tape reels, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 84.1, Folder R.1, R.1, R.3, R.4)
  - Mike Enis, Interview, March, 1976; Dubbed tape contains interview with Enis regarding his musical career including discussion about types of music from Southern Arizona: norteño; chicken scratch, waila. Collected by James S. Griffith in Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 84.6, Folder R.1)
  - First Annual All Tohono O’Odham Old Time Fiddle Orchestra Contest, 2nd Annual Wa:k Pow Wow, March 10, 1984; Tape contains performances by the San Simeon Great Time Band, the Schuk Doak Old Timers, the Edmund Wilson Band, and the James Manuel Band, at the First Annual All-Tohono O’Odham Old Time Fiddle Contest held during the 2nd Annual Wa:k Powwow. Announcements are by James S. Griffith, Daniel Joaquin, and Mike Enis (in Tohono O’Odham). Recording made by KUAT Radio of Tucson, Arizona. Collected by David Sadler at 2nd Annual Wa:k Pow Wow in Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 12 in. (Box 84.9, Folder R.1)
  - Clarence Dankworth, Fiddle tunes, May 24, 1975; Tapes contain interview with and fiddle tunes performed by Dankworth with accompaniment by Tom and Martha Jennings on guitar and mandolin. Reel 1 songs: Lynchburg Town/Get along down to town/Quit that tickling me -- Durang's hornpipe -- Ride an old paint -- Saddle old Spike/Take me back to Mammy/Take me back to Tulsa/Cowtown -- Arkansas Traveler... Reel 2 songs: Rabbit, where's your mammy -- Raccoon -- Ida Red -- Rye whiskey... Reel 3 songs: Sally Goodin' -- Old Joe Clark -- Sally Ann -- Great big taters... Reel 4 songs: Cacklin' Hen -- Soldier's joy -- Little Liza Jane -- Faded love/Soldier's march -- Cracklin' bread -- Run nigger, run... Reel 5 songs: Uncle Joe -- Smokin'[?]... Transcripts available in 84.11/R.1.T, 84.11/R.2.T, 84.11/R.3.T, 84.11/R.4.T and 84.11/R.5.T.. Collected by Clarence Dankworth in Safford, Arizona. 5 sound tape reels, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 5 in. (Box 84.11, Folder R.1, R.2, R.3, R.4, R.5)
  - Clarence Dankworth, Home recordings, undated; Tape contains copies of home recorded disks of fiddle tunes performed by Dankworth and accompanied by various friends. Songs are interspersed with recordings from various country music shows broadcast during the 1940's and 1950's...songs include: Letter from the girl -- Gray mare/Ragtime Annie -- Kentucky waltz/Sally Goodin -- Double Eagle -- Sally Gooden -- Untitled -- Untitled -- Glory bound train -- Put my little shoes away -- Idia Red -- Sally Goodin -- Dill pickle -- Chicken reel -- Leather britches -- Johnson girl -- Sally Goodman -- Rabbit, where's your mammy -- Sally Goodman -- Untitled -- Untitled -- Eight of January -- George York -- Leavin' Shian -- Eight of January -- Kacklin' Hen -- Lonesome Joe -- Chicken reel -- Walk along Johnny... Lists of songs available in file 84.11. Collected by Clarence Dankworth in Safford, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 84.11, Folder R.6)
  - Clarence Dankworth, Home recordings, undated; Tape contains copies of home recorded disks of fiddle tunes performed by Dankworth and accompanied by various friends. Songs are interspersed with recordings from various country music shows broadcast during the 1940's and 1950's...songs include: Lonesome Joe -- Big taters in Sandyland -- Apple blossom -- Sally Johnson -- Devel dream (Devil's dream) -- Saddel (Saddle) old Spike -- Untitled -- Johnson girl -- Gray mar' (mare) -- Gray Egul' (Eagle) -- Lost Indian -- Smoke on the water -- Turkey in the straw -- Redwing -- Untitled -- Untitled -- Take me back to Tulsa -- Prettiest girl in the country -- Billy Lowland -- Way down yondre (yonder) -- Fire in the mountains -- Turn your radio on -- Sally Gooden -- Soldier's joy -- Rabbit, where's your mammy -- Blue eyes -- Flop year mule -- Untitled -- Untitled -- Lonesome Joe -- Prettiest girl in the country -- Old Joe Clark -- Untitled... List of songs available in file 84.11.. Collected by Clarence Dankworth in Safford, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 84.11, Folder R.7)
  - Clarence Dankworth, Home recordings, undated; Tape contains copies of home recorded disks of fiddle tunes performed by Dankworth and accompanied by various friends. Songs are interspersed with recordings from various country music shows broadcast during the 1940's and 1950's...songs include: Untitled -- Sally Goodin -- Old Paint -- The Old red rooster -- Red River Valley -- Untitled -- Carless (Careless) darling -- Untitled -- Untitled -- Peekaboo waltz -- Greenback dollar -- Ragtime Annie -- Untitled waltz -- Rye whiskey -- Sindey (Cindy) -- Lonsum (Lonesome) blues -- Chicken reel -- Crippel (Cripple) Creek -- Casey Jones -- Untitled -- Leather britches -- Texas brakedown -- Irish washer woman... List of songs available in file 84.11. Collected by Clarence Dankworth in Safford, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 84.11, Folder R.8)
  - Clarence Dankworth, Home recordings, undated; Tape contains copies of home recorded disks of fiddle tunes performed by Dankworth and accompanied by various friends. Songs are interspersed with recordings from various country music shows broadcast during the 1940's and 1950's...songs include: Irish washer woman -- Saddle old Spike -- The Girl I left behind -- Hen Cackle Inn -- Ant going rain any (Ain't going to rain any...) -- Boil tem cabbage (Boil 'em cabbage) -- Solgers joy (Soldier's joy) -- Arkansas Traveller -- Chicken reel -- Prettiest girl in the country -- Blue eyed dazey -- Sally Goodman -- Sally Goodin -- Turkey in the straw -- Arkansas Traveller -- Untitled -- Big taters in Sandyland -- George York -- Lonesome Joe -- Take [me] back to Tulsa -- Rubber Dolly -- Idi Red -- Sally Goodin -- Redwing -- Marry me, pretty miss... List of songs available in file 84.11. Collected by Clarence Dankworth in Safford, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 84.11, Folder R.9)
  - Clarence Dankworth, Home recordings, undated; Tape contains copies of home recorded disks of fiddle tunes performed by Dankworth and accompanied by various friends. Songs are interspersed with recordings from various country music shows broadcast during the 1940's and 1950's...songs include: Idi Red -- Burt Stump -- Lonesome blues -- Untitled/There's a little bit of everything in Texas -- Smoke on the water -- Lizia Jane -- Faded love -- Appel (Apple) blossom -- Cripple Creek -- Boil cabbage -- Buffalo gals... list for side A available in file 84.11. Collected by Clarence Dankworth in Safford, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 84.11, Folder R.10)
  - Clarence Dankworth, Home recordings, undated; Tape contains copies of home recorded disks of fiddle tunes performed by Dankworth and accompanied by various friends. Songs are interspersed with recordings from various country music shows broadcast during the 1940's and 1950's...selections include: Old Blue -- Low and lonely -- Gladiola Flour commercial -- Sweet bye and bye -- Bedded roses -- Redwing... KOA radio in Denver: Lights in the valley outshine the sun -- Get along home Cindy -- Coming from the ball -- I called and nobody answered -- It'll aggravate your soul... Cloud Rea Radio: Wartime PA advertisement -- Miss McCloud's Reel... We'll understand it better bye and bye -- Soldier's joy -- Get along home Miss Cindy -- Billy in lowground -- Only a bird in a gilded cage -- I wish I was single again -- I wish I was single again (2) -- Maple on the hill -- Live and let live -- Soldier's joy -- Old Joe Clark -- Why do you bob your hair girls -- I'll be a friend to Jesus -- Irish washer woman -- Deep Ellum blues -- Comin' round the mountain -- Nobody's business but my own -- Open up them pearly gates -- Did you ever hear a church bell toll -- Ain't nobody gonna miss me when I'm gone -- Smoke on the water -- Oh Susannah -- My wild Irish Rose... List of songs available in file 84.11. Collected by Clarence Dankworth in Safford, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 84.11, Folder R.11)
  - Virgil H.Hamby, "Wild Horse Shorty", Interview, March 30, 1978; Tape contains interview with and songs performed by "Shorty" with his own guitar accompaniment... Graveyard blues -- Bill Moser's Ford -- Home sweet home -- I don't love nobody -- Late last night when Willie came home -- Hawaiian harmonics -- Heaven came down and glory filled my soul -- Twelfth Street rag... transcript available in 84.15/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 15 ips, 10 in. (Box 84.15, Folder R.1)
  - Virgil H.Hamby, "Wild Horse Shorty", Interview, April 17, 1978; Tape includes interview with, songs and stories performed by "Shorty"... Cowboy's heaven -- The Great plains -- Flip, flop and fly -- Zebra Dun -- Hobo convention -- Buffalo nickel/Desert blues -- Pride of the prairie, Mary my own -- Cowpunching 1931/D-2 wrangler -- John's new barn -- Of course, that's none of my business -- It can be done -- Ridge running roan -- Bury me out on the prairie/I've got no use for women -- Red ball freight -- Farewell to you, Stonewall... Transcript available in 84.15/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith and Mike Orr in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 10 in. (Box 84.15, Folder R.2)
  - Wild Horse Shorty, Interview, June 1, 1978; Tape contains stories, songs and fiddle tunes performed by "Shorty"... Stories and songs: Red ball freight -- Little Blossom -- Fiddle tunes: Flop-eared mule -- Heel and toe polka -- Schottische -- Leather britches -- Train story -- Uncle Bunt Stevens story -- Sweet Evalina waltz -- Old Joe Clark -- Turkey in the straw -- Sambo/Fire on the hillside -- Soldier's joy... Transcript available in file 84.15/R.3. Collected by James S. Griffith. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 15 ips, 10 in. (Box 84.15, Folder R.3)
  - Wild Horse Shorty, Interview, June 1, 1978; Tape contains stories, songs and fiddle tunes performed by "Shorty"...songs include: Bonaparte's retreat -- Drunken hiccups -- I'll fly away (with accompaniment by Bessie Hamby, wife) -- Walnut stump stomp -- Golden slippers -- Fisher's hornpipe -- Flop-eared mule -- Sail away ladies -- Waltz in D -- Chicken reel -- Irish washer woman -- Wagner... Transcript available in file 84.15/R.4. Collected by James S. Griffith. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 15 ips, 10 in. (Box 84.15, Folder R.4)
  - Bert Whetton, Cowboy songs, February 15, 1977; Tape contains interview with and songs performed by Burt Whetton, a Mormon cowboy from the Chihuahua Colonies, Mexico. The interview took place at the V.A. Hospital in Tucson, AZ, where Whetton was a patient. The guitar was loaned by James S. Griffith. Songs include: Rooster and hen -- Hell in Texas -- Goldurn wheel -- Song about women -- Barefoot boy with boots on -- Seven years with the wrong woman -- Great American Bum -- Don't you believe it -- You ask me why I am a hobo... Transcript available in file 84.16/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith and Barney Burns at the V. A. Hospital in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 10 in. (Box 84.16, Folder R.1)